Guide to the Church League of America Collection of the Research Files of Counterattack, the Wackenhut Corporation, and Karl Baarslag TAM.148
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Counterattack Research Files, 1928-1967
  - Subseries VI: Organizations, 1928-1967; 1940-1965
    - Non-Communist, Essentials for Trade Unionsim (Manual) (15-0, 56-150), circa 1947 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - American Legion (15-1), 1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - The Catholic Church - Vatican (15-2), 1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Plain Talk (15-3), 1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Government Officals (15-4), 1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - National Majority, Inc, aka United White Collar Majority, Inc. (15-5), 1945-1946 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - Speech Material - JQA - John Quincy Adams Associates (15-6), 1946 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - National Institute of Social Relations, Inc. (15-7), 1946 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - John Quincy Adams Associates, Inc. (15-8), 1946 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - Committee for Democratic Trade Unionism, CIO (15-9), 1947 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - American Veterans Committee (15-10), 1946-1953 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - Atomic Energy Control Commission (15-11), 1946-1953 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - Reverend John F. Cronin (15-12), 1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 46)
    - Reverend Andrew P. Moloney (15-13), 1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - Joseph Regelson (15-14), 1943-1947 (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - Gardiner Hawkins (15-17), 1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - Foreign Policy Association (15-18), 1947 (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - Sampson Horn (15-19), 1947 (Box 19, Folder 51)
    - Coplon-Gubitchev Case - 1st Trial - May 25, 1949 (15-20), Mar 1949-Jul 1949 (Box 19, Folder 52-54)
    - Alger Hiss Trial - First Trial - May 3, 1949 (15-21), Dec 1948-Jul 1949 (Box 20, Folder 1, Box 19, Folder 55-56)
    - Reference Material on Compulsory Sickness Insurance - Issued by the National Physicians Committee for the Extension of Medical Service (15-22), 1942-1945 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Medical Services Foundation; National Physicians Committee (15-22A), 1947-1949 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Newsletter (15-23), 1947 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Counterattack - Publicity (15-23A), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Free Enterprise - Planned Economy (15-24), 1947 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper - "P.M." (15-26), 1940-1946 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Youthbuilders (15-27), 1945-1946 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Americans for Democratic Action (15-28), 1946-1959 (Box 20, Folder 9-10)
    - Council Against Intolerance in America (15-29), 1946-1948 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Universities/Colleges, Miscellaneous (15-31), 1947 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - City College of New York [Student Strike] (15-31A), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (15-33), 1947-1954 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (15-33, supplement A), 1953-1956 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (15-33, supplement B), 1947-1959 (Box 20, Folder 16-18)
    - American China Policy Association (15-34), 1928, 1946-1949 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - American Jewish League Against Communism (15-35), 1948-1949 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - American Rally (15-36), Circa 1953 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - "Old Man Atom" (song) / Tenants and consumers organizations (50-1), 1947 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Screen Cartoonists (Guild) (50-2), 1946-1950 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Farmers Union (50-3), 1947-1955 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - American Communications Association (50-4), 1946-1954 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Challenge /New Challenge (50-5), 1950-1953 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Consumers Union (50-6), 1941-1951 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Insurance Union - United Office and Professional Workers of America and United Financial Employees (50-7), 1940s-1950s (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - UOPWA and Bankers Trust Strike (50-8), 1946-1947 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - People's Artists, Inc. / Art Editions / Liberty Book Club (50-9), 1954-1955 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Investigation of Dave Beck (Teamsters Union) (50-10), 1957 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - National Student Association (50-11), 1947-1955 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - CP leaders, group 3, California (50-12), 1951-1953 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - CP leaders, group 4, Baltimore (50-13), 1951-1953 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - CP leaders, group 5, Pittsburgh (50-14), 1950-1953 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - CP leaders, group 8, Honolulu (50-15), 1952-1953 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - CP leaders, group 7, Detroit (50-16), 1952-1954 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - CP leaders, group 9, Seattle (50-17), 1953 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - CP leaders, group 10, St. Louis (50-18), 1952 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - CP leaders, group 11, Philadelphia (50-19), 1953 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - CP leaders, group 10, Cleveland (50-20), 1953 (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - YMCA - YWCA (50-22), 1948-1949 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Youth Problems, Inc. / Youthbuilders, Inc. (50-23), 1946-1950 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - Young Progressives of America (50-24), 1948-1950 (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - American Association of Scientific Workers (50-25), 1950-1954 (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - Artists' Equity Association (Including Actors' Equity) (50-27), 1948-1955 (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - Letters of Denial via McNamara (Editor, Counterattack) [re: Spanish Refugee Appeal of the Joint Anti-Fascists Refugee Committee] (50-28), 1948-1956 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Young People's Records, Inc. (50-29), 1948-1950 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Young People's Record Club (50-30), 1950 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Names - Miscellaneous Reports, A-Z [Addes, Berney, Blauenstein, Cammer, Robinson, Rubin, Schneider, Shuford, Trilling, etc.] (50-31), 1946-1947 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Organizations - Miscellaneous Reports, A-Z [Armenian Fronts, American Council for a Democratic Greece, Civil Rights Congress, Communist Party, ICCASP, In Fact, Jefferson School, Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, Peron-Stalin Axis, UE School, etc.] (50-32), 1946-1947 (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
    - Illinois (50-33, Vol. I, items 1-82A), Feb 4, 1946-Feb 13, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 7-9)
    - Illinois (50-33, Vol. II, items 84-244), Feb 17, 1948-Sep 9, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 10-13)
    - Illinois (50-33, Vol. III, items 245-446), Sep 2, 1948-Jun 29, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 14-18)
    - Illinois (50-33, Vol. IV), Jul 1, 1949-Oct 20, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 19-23)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (50-34), 1949-1967 (Box 21, Folder 24-25)
    - American Bar Association (50-35), 1959-1965 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - American Communication Association (50-36), 1957 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - American Forum for Socialist Education (50-37), 1957 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - All-American Conference to Combat Communism (50-38), 1957 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born (50-39), 1956-1965 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - American Friends of the Captive Nations (50-40), 1956-1958 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - American Newspaper Guild (50-41), 1947-1957 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - The American Socialist (50-42), 1955-1958 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - American Foundation for Political Education (50-43), 1957-1958 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - American Friends Service Committee (50-44), 1954-1958 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - American mothers visit sons in China prisons (50-45), 1958 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Anti-Communist Legislation (50-46), 1950-1954 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Atomic Bombs and Missiles (50-47), 1957 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Attorney General's List (50-48), 1958 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Max Ascoli and The Reporter (50-49), 1950-1954 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Canadian Communism (50-50), 1949-1954 (Box 22, Folder 10-11)
    - Project X - Artwork (50-50A), 1954 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Project X - Correspondence (50-50B), 1954 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Alinsky, Saul (50-51), 1965-1967 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Art Students League of New York (50-52), 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Bettis, Valerie (50-53), 1953 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Bakers' Union (50-54), 1946-1964 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Barenblatt, Lloyd (50-55), 1958-1959 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Bildenberg Group, conferences (50-56), 1957-1965 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - The John Birch Society (50-57), 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Books (50-58), 1957 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Heywood Brown Memorial Award (50-59), 1948-1958 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Brussels International Trade Fair (50-60), 1958 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Louis Budenz' column ["The Reds - What Now?" in The Tablet] (50-61), 1958-1959 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - California Institute of Technology (50-62), 1950 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Canadian Intelligence Service (50-63), 1965-1967 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Catherwood Foundation (50-64), 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Christian Anti-Communism Crusade (50-65), 1958 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Chicago, University of (50-66), circa 1950-1958 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Circuit Riders (50-67), 1958 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - The Communist Party USA (manuscript) (50-68), 1965 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Communist Party USA, 16th National Convention (50-69), 1955-1957 (Box 22, Folder 32-33)
    - Congress of Freedom, Inc. (50-70), 1958 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Council Against Communist Agression (50-71), 1957-1958 (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Council for a Livable World (50-72), 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Cultural Exchange with Russia (50-73), 1958 (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Elmer Davis Memorial Committee (50-74), 1958 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Let Freedom Ring! Declaration of Independence, signers of (50-75), 1965-1966 (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Dewey, Thomas E. Jr. (50-76), 1964 (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - du Berrier, Hilaire (50-77), 1955-1958 (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Downtown Community School (50-78), 1953-1955 (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - Eaton, Cyrus (50-79), 1951-1958 (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - Eichelberger, Ted (50-80), 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (50-81), 1955-1965 (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - FBI (50-82), 1955 (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - Fluoridation (50-83), 1954-1958 (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Foreign Policy Association (50-84), 1961-1966 (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Fund for the Republic (50-85), 1952-1965 (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - Gordon Hall (50-86), 1947-1964 (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - Harvard Law School Publications (50-87), 1957-1959 (Box 22, Folder 51)
    - Harvard University (50-88), 1950-1958 (Box 22, Folder 52)
    - Hawaii Residents Association, Inc. (50-89), 1949-1958 (Box 22, Folder 53)
    - Hawaiian Residents Association - IMUA Spotlight newsletter (50-90), 1950-1953 (Box 23, Folder 1-3)
    - Health Research - California (50-91), 1950s (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Heikkila, William (50-92), 1957-1958 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - HUAC (50-93), 1952-1955 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - General Hugh B. Hester (50-94), 1957-1958 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Highlander Folk School (50-95), 1953-1958 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Hillman, Sidney (50-96), 1962 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Hiss, Alger (50-97), 1955 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Hoover, J. Edgar and the FBI (50-98), 1959 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Hydrogen Bomb/Nuclear Fallout (50-99), 1958 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Immigration (50-100), 1950-1967 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Jews - Birobidzhan (50-101), 1958 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Johnson - Syracuse (50-102), 1954-1955 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Kerbs, Jeanne E. (50-103), 1959-1967 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Kirstein, George G. (50-104), 1959 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Knowland, Sen. William F. (50-105), 1958 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Lamont, Corliss (50-106), 1955 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Emma Lazarus Federation of Jewish Women's Clubs, Inc. (50-107), 1957-1958 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - League of Women Voters (50-108), 1955-1965 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Liberty Book Club (50-109), 1955 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - McCarran Act - Internal Security Act (50-110), 1955 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - McCormack, Reveverend Peter (50-111), 1958 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - McCullough, Hester R. (50-112), 1949-1950 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Meagher, Robert (50-113), 1958 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Mental Health [Dr. Fred Schwartz and Christian Anti-Communism Crusade] (50-114), 1959-1960 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Methodist Federation for Social Action (50-115), 1935-1960 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Methodist Ministers [Circuit Riders, Inc.] (50-116), 1959 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Mexico (50-117), 1958 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Militant Labor Forum (50-118), circa 1950s (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Milwaukee Journal [Transcript of "Bob Siegrist and the News," radio show] (50-119), Jul 19, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Musicians' Union Local 802 [Constitution and bylaws] (50-120), 1955, 1957-1958 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Musicians' Union - Local 802 [President Al Manuti; includes four issues of Allegro newspaper] (50-120), 1937-1958 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Musicians' Union - Local 802 [Includes correspondence with President Al Manuti] (50-120), 1937-1958 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Musicians' Union - Local 802 [Includes correspondence with President Al Manuti, union ballots] (50-120), 1937-1958 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (50-121), 1957 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy [Includes reports from Long Island committee meetings] (50-122), 1957-1960 (Box 23, Folder 38-42)
    - National Committee to Win Amnesty for the Smith Act Victims (50-123), 1955 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - National Council of Christians and Jews (50-124), 1951-1958 (Box 23, Folder 44-45)
    - National Council of Churches (50-125), 1941-1960 (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - National Council of Churches (50-125), 1941-1960 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - National Lawyers Guild (50-127), 1955-1957 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - New York Civil Liberties Union (50-128), 1946-1967 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - News [and Bulletin, Film Institute for the Study of the USSR] (50-129), 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - New School for Social Research (50-130), 1964 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - New York State -- Education [Board of Higher Education of the City of New York] (50-131), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Northern Neighbors [Includes Copy of New Masses and The Worker Magazine and Material for Film on "Peace Walks] (50-132), 1946-1958 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Passports (50-133), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Peru (50-134), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Pizer, Morris - United Furniture Workers [Includes Materials to be Filed Under Poland - Marek Hlasko] (50-135), 1949-1950, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Polaris - Atomic Power (50-137), 1958-1961 (Box 24, Folder 11-13)
    - Powell-Schuman Defense Fund (50-138), 1950, 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Princeton University (50-139), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Religion (50-140), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Religious Freedom Committee (50-141), 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Religious Freedom News (50-142), 1954 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Retail Clerks International Union (50-143), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Roosevelt University [The Torch] (50-144), April 1958 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Russia and Satellites - Uprisings (50-145), 1956 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Schwarz, Dr. Fred C. [Christian Anti-Communism Crusade] (50-146), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Security (50-147), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Senate Internal Security (50-148), 1959 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Servicemen's Defense Committee (50-149), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Shaw, Irwin (50-150), 1949-1958 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Sheiner, Leo (50-151), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Socialist Unity Forum (50-152), 1957 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Socialist Youth Committee of Chicago (50-153), 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Southern Conference Educational Fund [Includes The Untouchables with illustrations by Ben Shahn and sixteen issues of The Southern Patriot] (50-154), 1949-1954 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Soviet Elections [Includes USSR Magazine] (50-155), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Soviet Periodicals [Includes correspondence with Arthur Hays Sulzberger, Publisher of New York Times] (50-156), 1955 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Stern, Alfred K. (50-157), 1956-1958 (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Subversive Activities Control Board (50-158), 1955 (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Summit Conference (50-159), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - "The Tablet" Editorials [Catholic Weekly Newspaper] (50-160), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Taiwan - Red China [Includes some clippings in Chinese and English language magazines on China] (50-161), 1963-1965 (Box 24, Folder 37-38)
    - Union Racketeering (50-162), Mar 11, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - The United Nations - The United Auto Workers (50-163), 1958, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) (50-164), 1955, 1959, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - The Unitarians (50-165), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - Upholsters' International Union of America (50-166), 1957-1959 (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - Van Horne, Harriet (50-167), 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - Wanamaker's Department Store Workers Union [Local No. 9, New York City] (50-168), 1949-1958 (Box 24, Folder 45)
    - Wingenbach, Charles E. (50-169), 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 46)
    - World Court (50-170), 1960 (Box 24, Folder 47)
    - World Peace Through Law Center [American Bar Association] (50-171), 1965 (Box 24, Folder 48)
    - World Youth Festival - Sixth [Includes Counterattack Index Cards] (50-172), 1957-1959 (Box 24, Folder 49-50)
    - Crockett, William J. [George Crockett] (50-173), circa 1950-1966 (Box 24, Folder 51)
    - Yale University (50-174), 1949 (Box 24, Folder 52)
    - Council Against Communist Aggression and Alexis de Tocqueville Society (50-175), 1958-1964 (Box 24, Folder 53-56)
    - [Two Unaccounted Reports: American Coalition of Patriotic Societies; "Excerpt from Bob Siegrist and the News, March 1, 1960"], 1960, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 57)
  - Subseries VII: Foundations, 1942-1966
    This series consists of files kept on foundations for the purposes of monitoring officers and staff, areas and amounts of giving and grant recipients to identify relationships among foundations and suspected Communists and front organizations. There is an emphasis on educational institutions, as well as labor leaders, journalists, writers, and artists receiving direct or indirect support from foundations.
    Files include typed profiles of foundations, press coverage on foundation initiatives, and foundation publications. The series also contains several files of individual and foundation profiles which cross reference other Counterattack research and library files.
    - List of Foundations (21-0) [Includes "Information Re: Organization of Foundation File"], circa 1947 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Joint and General References - Serials 1-45 (21-0A), circa 1947 (Box 25, Folder 2-3)
    - Joint and General References - Serials 46-82 (21-0B), circa 1947 (Box 25, Folder 4-5)
    - Joint and General References - Serials 83-88 (21-0C), 1950-1952 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - American Fund for Public Service (21-1), 1947 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Carnegie Corporation of New York (21-2), 1947 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Carnegie Endowment of International Peace (21-3), circa 1947 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Field Foundation, Inc. (21-5), circa 1940s (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Edward A. Filene Good Will Fund, Inc. (21-6), 1947 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (21-8), 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Robert Marshall Civil Liberties Trust (21-10), undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Robert Marshall Foundation (21-11), 1948 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Robert Marshall Wilderness Fund (21-12), circa 1947 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (21-13), 1947-1949 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Re: Cornell University) (21-13A), 1943-1947 (Box 25, Folder 17-19)
    - Russell Sage Foundation (21-15), 1947 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation (Publications) -- Serials 16-54 (21-16 1A) [Includes New York University Institute on Postwar Reconstruction], 1943-1947 (Box 25, Folder 21-22)
    - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Vol. 1 - Serials 1-9 (21-16) [Includes New York University Department of Film], 1947 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Vol. II - Serials 10-197 (21-16), 1947 (Box 25, Folder 24-26)
    - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Vol. III - Serials 198-244 (21-16), 1940-1946 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Twentieth Century Fund, Inc. (21-18), 1947-1966 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - William C. Whitney Foundation (21-19), 1942-1947 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Ford Foundation (21-20), 1953 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - California Intelligence Bureau (21-20[?]), 1952-1953 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Subseries VIII: Reports on Individuals and Organizations, 1946-1965
    This subseries mostly contains prepared reports created by Counterattack on individuals, unions, and other organizations, the bulk of which were created in the late 1940s and 1950s. These reports consist of information on activities and biographical and historical information on individuals and organizations that were considered Communist or sympathetic to Communists. These reports were a compilation of information that they collected, typed and often marked with one of the editors' initials in the corner of the report. The reports referenced any left-wing or Communist-linked activity of the individuals or organizations. Often these reports were created for people outside of ABC.
    In addition to reports, reference requests toward Counterattack's research department are included; they consist of an internal reference sheet and handwritten notes on the researched individual. Indexes are also found in the series; cross-referencing individuals and organizations found in earlier series. Some of the indexes include references to the listed individuals in left-wing publications like The Daily Worker or Soviet Russia Today, in New York-based news source such as the New York Times and the New York Herald Tribune, or in the reports on suspected subversive individuals compiled by Senator Jack B. Tenney, the chairman of the California Senate Factfinding Subcommittee on Un-American Activities. Other indexes include references to the individuals in this series in Appendix IX. Some of the internal reports within this series are duplicated in Series V. Counterattack's numbering scheme is maintained on earlier series to aid cross-referencing. Some of these individuals and organizational reports are duplicates that appear in different series within the collection.
    Arrangement
    This series is arranged alphabetically.
    - Reports: Aaron - Aglonsky, 1950-1958 (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Reports: Albert - American Association of Scientific Workers, 1948-1954 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Report: American Civil Liberties Union, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Reports: American Committee for Chinese War Orphans - American Youth for Democracy, 1949-1953 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Reports: Americans for Democratic Action - Antioch College, 1949-1953 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Reports: Armitage - Averill, 1949-1954 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Reports: Bacall - Barnes, 1948-1953 (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Reports: Barr, 1953, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - Reports: Barry - Bay, 1949-1956 (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Reports: Beal - Bettis, 1949-1955 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Reports: Bially - Blaisdell, 1948-1954 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Reports: Blanch - Book Find Club, 1948-1954 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Reports: Borge - Brandt, 1948-1954 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Reports: Brewery Unions, 1945-1958 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Reports: Brickman - Brown, 1949-1955 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Reports: Brozen - Bundy, 1949-1955 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Reports: Burke - Burton, 1949-1953 (Box 26, Folder 8)